Peter Wright

A highly motivated and adaptable Online Learning Designer/Developer with a wide range of skills including multimedia creation as well as responsive support, seeking a position within a strong forward-thinking team.

I have excellent attention to detail and problem solving skills. I'm a strong communicator, always committed to learning new skills and build upon existing knowledge gained from 15 years in the IT/creative industry. Now looking to join a team that is keen to recruit an experienced multi-skilled developer to work on challenging and interesting new projects as well as revamping existing ones.

Areas of Expertise:

- Multimedia Development
- Adobe Creative Suite (Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, Animate/Flash, Audition)
- Video Editing (e.g. Adobe Premiere Pro, After Effects)
- Articulate Storyline/Rise
- HTML5/CSS
- E-Learning / Online Learning
- UX/UI Design
- Customer support

Career Summary

Digital Learning Designer

Alcumus, Cardiff (April 2022 - Present)

My current role at Alcumus involves the consultation, design, development and implementation of digital solutions for Alcumus colleagues.

This ranges from the initial consultation with the SME regarding their request (whether that be a course or alternative resource), to the hands-on creation itself (using authoring tools such as Articulate Storyline or Rise), as well as the additional creation or resources via tools such as Adobe Illustrator, Photoshop, Premier Pro/After Effects for videos or animations, or InDesign for PDF/Infographic requests.

I'm also involved in the administration of Alcumus' Learning Management System (LMS), including the uploading of new or updated content, looking into and fixing issues from user queries, or regularly updating the site itself to improve the user experience where possible.

Learning Designer

Astutis Ltd., Cardiff (May 2021 – April 2022)

My returning role at Astutis was a 12-month contract primarily client-facing where I liaised with Astutis' clients regarding their requirements for new courses (St John Ambulance being my main contact), followed by the creation of online learning content as per their requests.

Day to day responsibilities included:

- Course development using authoring tools such as Articulate Storyline and HTML5.
- Working with the in-house graphic designers to create assets to incorporate within the blended courses.
- Voiceover setup and recording, as well as the editing process using sound recording software (Adobe Audition
- Video editing using Adobe Premier Pro.
- Testing other team member's projects and leaving feedback when issues are spotted. Fixing any issues where I could too.

Digital Learning Designer

Royal Voluntary Service (RVS), Cardiff (May 2017 – Feb 2021)

At RVS, I was responsible for the running of the E-Learning output. This role required that I seamlessly take over from the previous Digital Learning Designer during maternity leave cover, and eventually brought on for a full-time position.

My role as Digital Learning Designer at Royal Voluntary Service covered a wide range of duties and responsibilities including:

Page 1 of 3 Tel: 07746 733127

Email: peter_j_wright@outlook.com

Peter Wright

- Responsible for the creation of the RVS E-Learning output to populate their E-Learning website using Articulate Storyline as the main piece of software.
- Regular use of design skills within Adobe Photoshop as well as the rest of the Adobe Creative Suite to produce blended learning materials such as videos, PDF documents and imagery.
- The handling of all user queries and issues via phone and email to provide support and help to users (be they volunteers or employees) to overcome the problems they may have had with the Learning site such as trouble logging in, problems viewing the courses due to technical issues, or user capabilities.
- Regular uploading of volunteers or employees to the Learning site once they have joined RVS.
- Utilising my video editing skills for projects throughout the charity, including the social media output such as the RVS Virtual Village Hall collection.
- Managing of the RVS E-Learning site as well as the re-building and modifications involved to make it as userfriendly as possible for the RVS audience (utilising my HTML5 skills).

Multimedia Developer

Astutis Ltd., Nantgarw (May 2011 – Jan 2017)

- A member of the E-Learning team creating web-based Health and Safety training courses including IOSH H&S courses, NEBOSH H&S courses, including their international equivalents built around their respective legislation.
- Programs were initially created using Adobe Flash but later moved on to more modern and compatible technologies, which required learning and utilising HTML5. The development work included building custom CSS files to use in conjunction with the HTML files as well as incorporating Javascript.
- · Responsible for Digital Asset Management (DAM). Built and maintained a large catalogue of assets and images in multiple formats as required for online training and marketing purposes.
- · Used Adobe InDesign to create PDF training course notes to accompany both online training courses and classroom based training hosted by Astutis across the UK and abroad.
- Created high-quality marketing videos and edited using Adobe Premiere Pro, showcasing Astutis courses to potential clients. These videos are available on YouTube and embedded within the relevant course content.
- Development of 3D content using Blender for modelling characters, scenes, equipment, etc. Content also required syncing to voice-over, which I was involved in setting up and recording.
- Assisted the Marketing department with creation of images and assets to be sent in client emails, and to be incorporated into online noticeboards and flyers.

IT Developer

Silicon Edge, Penarth (Feb 2011 – May 2011)

- · Responsible for assisting the production team with various creative projects, including developing prototype layouts for websites, databases and projection systems using Sketchflow.
- Also tasked with maintaining client websites using custom CMS tools. Updates also included creating web compliant assets using Adobe Photoshop and Illustrator.
- The role included testing responsibilities to ensure the quality of completed work before customer sign-off.

IT Developer

Simpson Communications Ltd., Cowbridge (May 2009 – Dec 2010)

- Was a key member of a software development team producing and implementing online training systems and E-Learning software solutions.
- Used software packages for production including Adobe Photoshop, Flash and Dreamweaver alongside programming languages including HTML and XML.
- · Was also required to undertake onsite work (photography/filming) alongside programming, testing and product sign off.

Tel: 07746 733127 Page 2 of 3

Email: peter_j_wright@outlook.com

Peter Wright

- Customer projects included creating site inductions and training programs for E.ON UK, Scottish and Southern Energy (SSE) and BLCP Power Station (Thailand).
- Other skills gained during my role at Simpson Communications include photography, video editing and dealing with end user queries.

Customer Assistant

Tesco, Talbot Green (Jan 2005 - Aug 2009)

- Worked part-time as a Customer Assistant while studying at University. The role involved dealing with customers and other members of staff (including assisting new members with training).
- Gained valuable communication and problem solving skills during my time in Tesco which have been an
 asset throughout my career.

Qualifications

Academic

BSc (Hons) - Creative Technologies* (2:1) (*Course title was originally "Digital Media & Broadcasting Technologies" in Year 1)

University of South Wales (University of Glamorgan - ATRiuM) - 2005-2008

Other Qualifications

CIM* Level 3 Award in Marketing Principles – Distinction	Oct 2017	*Chartered Institute of Marketing
CIM Level 3 Award in Digital Essentials – Merit	Oct 2017	
NEBOSH NGC2 (Controlling workplace hazards)	Aug 2016	
NEBOSH NGC3 (Health and Safety Practical Application)	Aug 2016	
Adobe Flash Advanced Training	May 2009	
City & Guilds Professional Development Award	May 2009	

0-4-0047

Personal

Was a member of the charity committee at Astutis helping to organise events for their chosen charities, while I also undertook the role of Fire Warden at Astutis.

Actively compete in various challenges for charity, including various 10K runs around the South Wales area, and have many more challenges lined up for the future.

Full, clean driving licence.

Page 3 of 3 Tel: 07746 733127

Email: peter_j_wright@outlook.com